<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>org.electrum.electrum</id>
  <name>Electrum</name>
  <developer_name>Thomas Voegtlin, et al.</developer_name>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">org.electrum.electrum.desktop</launchable>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>
  <summary>Lightweight Bitcoin client</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
      Electrum's focus is speed and simplicity, with low resource usage. It uses remote servers that handle the most complicated parts of the Bitcoin system, and it allows you to recover your wallet from a secret phrase.
    </p>
    <p>
      Do not trust. Verify.
    </p>
    <p>
      Electrum verifies that your transactions
      are in the Bitcoin blockchain.

      Because Bitcoin is not about trust,
      It is about freedom and independence.
    </p>
    <p>
      Main features are:
    </p>
    <ul>
      <li>Safe: Your private keys are encrypted and never leave your computer</li>
      <li>Forgiving: Your funds can be recovered from a secret phrase</li>
      <li>Instant On: Electrum is fast, because it uses servers that index the Bitcoin blockchain</li>
      <li>No lock-In: You can export your private keys and use them in other Bitcoin clients</li>
      <li>No Downtimes: Electrum servers are decentralized and redundant. Your wallet is never down</li>
      <li>Proof Checking: Electrum Wallet verifies all the transactions in your history using SPV</li>
      <li>Cold Storage: Keep your private keys offline, and go online with a watching-only wallet</li>
      <li>Multisig: Split the permission to spend your coins between several wallets</li>
      <li>Add-ons: Electrum supports third-party plugins: Multisig services, Hardware wallets, etc</li>
    </ul>
  </description>

  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>MIT</project_license>

  <url type="homepage">https://electrum.org/</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/spesmilo/electrum/issues</url>
  <url type="help">http://docs.electrum.org/en/latest/</url>
  <translation></translation>

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/flathub/org.electrum.electrum/master/screenshots/electrum.png</screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <releases>
    <release date="2019-07-11" version="3.3.8">
      <description>
        <p>
          Electrum 3.3.8 is here with another round of fixes:
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fix some bugs with recent bump fee (RBF) improvements (#5483, #5502)</li>
          <li>Fix #5491: watch-only wallets could not bump fee in some cases</li>
          <li>Appimage: URLs could not be opened on some desktop environments (#5425)</li>
          <li>Faster tx signing for segwit inputs for really large txns (#5494)</li>
          <li>A few other minor bugfixes and usability improvements</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2019-07-03" version="3.3.7"/>
    <release date="2019-05-16" version="3.3.6"/>
    <release date="2019-05-09" version="3.3.5"/>
    <release date="2019-02-13" version="3.3.4"/>
    <release date="2019-01-25" version="3.3.3"/>
</releases>
<update_contact>msandova_at_protonmail.com</update_contact>
</component>
